# BHARGAV SAI RAM KATTUNGA Product Designer | UX/UI Designer | UX Researcher

Product Designer with 4+ years of experience in SaaS products, utilities, payment systems and enterprise platforms for mobile & web experiences. Specialized in UX research, interaction design, and data-driven decision-making to enhance product engagement and usability.

#### Skills and Tools

Research & Strategy: Human Factors, Cognitive Science, Problem Finding and Solving, Contextual Inquiry, User Research, Qualitative Analysis, A/B Testing, Usability Testing, Critical and Systems Thinking, Branding Strategy, Data Analysis UX Methods: Research Workshop, Journey Mapping, User Flows, User Personas, Experience Maps, Empathy Maps, Stakeholder Analysis, Behavioral Analysis, Accessibility Research, Data Visualization and Data-driven implementations Design & Prototyping: Storyboard, User Interface Design, Mobile App Design, Web Design, Responsive Design, Visual Design,Intuitive User experience, Interaction Design, Human-Computer Interaction, Design Systems, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Mockups

**Tools**: Figma, Adobe Creative Suite, uizard, Hotjar, Dovetail, Lookback, Optimal Workshop, Axure, Balsamiq, Google Workshop **Others**: User Stories, Collaboration, Decision Making, Team Management and Mentoring

## Professional Experience

# Cloud Resources | UX/UI Designer

06/2024 - Present, 10 months, Doha, Qatar

- Reduced customer onboarding time by 66% (from 30 to 10 minutes) through user journey optimization and strategic UX improvements for retail users.
- Spearheaded the UX/UI design of Doha Bank's corporate mobile app, resulting in user base conversion of 1.7% from internet banking.
- Drove user-centered design initiatives across retail and corporate banking divisions, unifying UX across platforms and increasing overall customer satisfaction scores by 20% within the first quarter.
- Drove the end-to-end implementation of 8 new retail mobile app features, focused on a streamlined development process; decreasing customer questions by 10% related to interlinked functionalities.
- Established and maintained a component-based design system, ensuring consistency across mobile and web platforms while accelerating development cycles for both divisions.
- Led stakeholder workshops to align business requirements with user needs, resulting in prioritized feature roadmap spread across the 1.5 months setup phase.

## **Leafcraft** | Product Designer

03/2022 - 06/2024, 02 years 04 month, Hyderabad, India

- Managed end-to-end design process for 25+ digital products, balancing user needs with business objectives.
- Architected scalable design systems that reduced development time by 40% while maintaining design consistency across products.
- Grew daily active users from 1-2 to 9+ within two months post-launch through iterative design improvements based on user research and A/B testing.
- Executed structured user interviews and A/B testing to validate design decisions and identify optimization opportunities.
- Pioneered the establishment of a design system within the company, enabling accelerated development and fostering the creation of captivating designs by upcoming designers.

# Capgemini | UX Designer/A4

09/2021 - 03/2022, 06 months, Hyderabad (Remote), India

- Led UX research and usability testing for enterprise applications, reducing error rates by 6% and improving user satisfaction.
- Conducted A/B testing and heuristic evaluations, providing data-driven insights to optimize internal application interfaces.
- Designed interactive wireframes and prototypes for internal systems, enhancing usability and workflow efficiency for employees.

- Increased beta user retention by 35% through implementation of voice-enabled UX features and interactive gameplay elements.
- Conducted user research with 50+ participants through surveys and 4 focus groups, achieving an 85% user satisfaction rate with MVP features.
- Conceptualized and prototyped five distinct user flows within Figma, achieving a 90% implementation rate by engineering, and demonstrably improved the onboarding process for first-time app users.

Other Projects

## Travana - Al-assisted travel app

10/2023 - 04/2024, 07 months, washington (Remote), USA

Led strategic design iterations resulting in 5 comprehensive pitch decks and 2 elevator decks, directly contributing to securing \$50K in initial funding.

- Architected end-to-end design system with 25+ reusable UI components and 10+ optimized user flows, reducing design-to-development efforts.
- Achieved 30-second average interaction time with initial cohort of 583 users, demonstrating strong early user engagement.

#### One Immersive - Immersive Tech

07/2022 - 10/2022, 03 months, Hyderabad, India

• Led development of comprehensive branding and guidelines for 3 immersive technology product lines (AR, VR, Mixed Reality), establishing unified design language and vision.

Leadership

## Adplist | Mentor

01/2023 - Present, 02 years 02 months, Online

- Ranked in top 30% of mentors globally among 2000+ design mentors on ADPList platform.
- Conducted 50+ 1:1 mentoring sessions with 90% positive feedback rate.
- Guided 12 mentees through portfolio development and interview preparation, resulting in successful transitions into UI/UX design roles at leading tech companies, and startups.

#### **Atal Innovation Mission India | Mentor**

02/2022 - 06/2024, 02 years 04 months, karimnagar, India

• Established and implemented STEM innovation programs in 3 pilot schools, creating a replicable framework for program expansion.

Education

## Coursera X Google Certified

05/2021, 01 months, Online

Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design

# Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

06/2017 - 08/2021, 04 years 01 months, Hyderabad, India

Bachelor's of Technology, Mechanical (Mechatronics) Engineering

- Published a paper Titled "Design and Fabrication of Water Rehydrator" in the International Research Journal of Engineering and Technology (IRJET), Paper ID: FTP804F2614, Volume 8, Issue 4, Apr 2021.
- Qualified in the Internal round of Smart India Hackathon-Hardware 2019, providing the solution for 'Bihar Agriculture Soil Testing'.
- Qualified for Semi-Final stage of IICDC 2020, conducted by Texas Instruments among top 784 teams for our project titled 'CHIROPRACTIC DEVICE'.